Register of the Joseph Shattan papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Joseph Shattan papers
1938-1991
85004
Hoover Institution Archives
54 manuscript boxes (22.5 linear feet)
Speeches of Jeane Kirkpatrick, Elliott Abrams, William Bennett, George Schultz, and Dan Quayle, letters, memoranda, testimony, bulletins, and printed matter relating to American foreign and domestic policy during the administrations of Ronald Reagan and George Bush, to human rights violations throughout the world, and to the United Nations.
Shattan, Joseph.
Kirkpatrick, Jeane J.
Bennett, William J. (William John), 1943-
Quayle, Dan, 1947-
Abrams, Elliott, 1948-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1985.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Counselor to United States Ambassador to the United Nations Jeane Kirkpatrick, 1981-1982, to Assistant Secretary of State for Human Rights Elliott Abrams, 1982-1985, to Secretary of Education William Bennett, 1985-1989, and to Vice President Dan Quayle, 1989-1991. Shattan was born in 1950 and died in 2014.
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection contains speeches of Jeane Kirkpatrick, Elliott Abrams, William Bennett, George Schultz, and Dan Quayle, letters, memoranda, testimony, bulletins, and printed matter relating to American foreign and domestic policy during the administrations of Ronald Reagan and George Bush, to human rights violations throughout the world, and to the United Nations.
United Nations.; United States. Department of State.; Civil rights.; United States--Politics and government--1981-1989.; United States--Politics and government--1989-1993.; United States--Foreign relations--1981-1989.; United States--Foreign relations--1989-1993.; Education--United States.; United States. Department of Education.; Reagan, Ronald.
- Correspondence, 1978-1991
  Scope and Contents note
  Memoranda
  - 1978-1982 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - 1983 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - 1984 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - 1985 (Box 2, Box-folder 3: 1)
  - 1986 (Box-folder 3: 2-3)
  - 1987 (Box-folder 3: 4, Box-folder 4: 1)
  - 1988 (Box-folder 4: 2-3)
  - 1990-1991 (Box-folder 4: 4)
- Notes, undated (Box 5, Box 6, Box-folder 7: 1)
- Speeches and Writings, 1981-1987, undated
  - "AIFLD Graduation Day Speech,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Ambassador Kirkpatrick's Solidarity Sunday Speech,", 1982 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "The Amsterdam News Letter to the Editor,", 1981 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Berlin Speech,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "CDUP Speech,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Contending Strains in American Foreign Policy,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Contingency Toast,", 1987 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Copy for Column 'Point of View',", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Democracy and Human Rights,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Disarmament and Development,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Draft Op-Ed for Faith Whittlesey,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "El Salvador: The View from Washington,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "The Evolution of the Carter Administration's Human Rights Policy,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Explanation of Vote on Item 19: Colonialism,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Explanation of Vote: Question of Palestine,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Georgetown Commencement Speech,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "How Not to Talk About El Salvador,", undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - "Israel, the U.S., and the U.N.,", undated (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - "Item 19: Colonialism,", undated (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - "Item 31: The Question of Palestine,", undated (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - "Item 81: Self Determination,", undated (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - "Kampuchea Speech,", undated (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - "Preliminary Remarks on U.S. History Textbooks,", undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - "Raoul Wallenberg Tribute,", undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - "Red Cross/Washington College Speech,", undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - "Reflections on the U.N.,", 1982 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - "The Registered Churches Are Captive Churches,", undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - "Religious Intolerance,", undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - "Remarks for Dean Burch Reception,", undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - "Right of Reply on Self-Determination for Puerto Rico,", undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - "Right of Reply on Soviet Colonialism,", undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - "Secretary's Remarks to Cong. Regula's Constituents,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "The Situation in Poland,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "Social Responsibility of the University,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "Soviet Jewry Statement,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "The Soviet-PLO Connection,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "Speech Before Young Republican Leadership Conference,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "Speech for Calvin Bullock Forum,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "Speech to DISSAM Students,", 1983 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "Statement for U.N. Ball,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "Talking Points for Chowder and Marching Society,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "Terrorism Speech,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "Third Committee Item 12: Human Rights in El Salvador,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "United Nations Day Statement,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "The United States and the United Nations: Thoughts for New Themes,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "USA Today Op-Ed,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "White House Statement on Raoul Wallenberg,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Speech on El Salvador politics, undated (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Speech on human rights and American foreign policy, undated (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Speech on human rights in El Salvador, undated (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Speech on the Red Cross, undated (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Speech on Western Civilization, undated (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Speech on higher education, undated (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Speech on higher education and Western Civilization, undated (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Speech on anti-American propaganda, undated (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Speech on human rights in the Soviet Union, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Speech on the Security Council, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Speech on Armistice Day, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Speech on the Camp David Framework, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Speech on the President of Niger, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Speech on Central America and the Caribbean, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Speech on anti-Communism, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
- Speeches by Others, 1964-1991
  - Abrams, Elliott, 1982-1988
    - 1982 (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - 1983
      - A-C (Box-folder 8: 3-5)
      - E-M (Box-folder 8: 6)
      - N-Z (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
    - 1984
      - A-F (Box-folder 9: 3-4)
      - G-M (Box-folder 9: 5)
      - N-P (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
      - R-Z (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - 1985-1988 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - Undated
      - A-B (Box-folder 10: 5)
      - C-F (Box-folder 11: 1)
      - G-M (Box-folder 11: 2)
      - N-R (Box-folder 11: 3)
      - S (Box-folder 11: 4)
      - T-Z (Box-folder 12: 1)
      - Untitled (Box-folder 12: 2-4)
  - Al-Nassar, Khaled, 1990 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Amnesty International, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Armacost, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Aronson, Bernard, 1990 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Aspin, Les, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Barry, Robert, 1991 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Bauer, Gary, 1985 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Bell, T. H., 1984 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Bennett, Tapley, 1976 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Bennett, William, 1985-1987
    - 1985
      - A-F (Box-folder 13: 8-9)
      - G-M (Box-folder 13: 10)
      - N-W (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
      - Untitled (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - 1986-1987 (Box-folder 14: 4-5)
    - Undated
      - A-Z (Box-folder 15: 1)
      - Untitled (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Bosworth, Stephen, 1982 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Brock, William, 1983 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Bush, George H. W., 1989-1991 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Cheney, Richard, 1989 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Cohen, Herman, 1991 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Conaway, John, 1989 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Curry, Jerry, 1986 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Dam, Kenneth, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Eagleburger, Lawrence, 1983-1991 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Einaudi, Luigi, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Enders, Thomas, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Epstein, Joyce, 1984 (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Fairbanks, undated (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Gates, Robert, 1991 (Box-folder 16: 11)
  - Gershman, Carl, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 16: 12)
  - Gingrich, Newt, 1985 (Box-folder 16: 13)
  - Gracey, James, undated (Box-folder 16: 14)
  - Griesgraber, JoMarie, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 15)
  - Hadi, Deborah, 1990 (Box-folder 16: 16)
  - Haft, Marilyn, 1980 (Box-folder 16: 17)
  - Hawke, R. J. L., 1988 (Box-folder 16: 18)
  - Howe, Harold, undated (Box-folder 16: 19)
  - Ikle, Fred, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 20)
  - Kampelman, Max, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 16: 21)
  - Kemble, Penn, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 22)
  - Kemp, Evan, 1981 (Box-folder 16: 23)
  - Keyes, Alan, 1984 (Box-folder 16: 24)
  - Klenk, Jack, 1984 (Box-folder 16: 25)
  - Kolakowski, Leszek, undated (Box-folder 16: 26)
  - Kirkpatrick, Jeanne, 1980-1983
    - 1980-1981 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - 1982
      - A-C (Box-folder 17: 2)
      - D-L (Box-folder 17: 3)
      - M-R (Box-folder 17: 4)
      - S-W (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - Undated (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Levitsky, Melvyn, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - Lewis, Samuel, 1985 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Lichenstein, Charles, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - London, Herbert, undated (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1964 (Box-folder 18: 8)
  - Matthews, Gary, 1983 (Box-folder 18: 9)
  - Michel, James, 1984 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  - Murphy, Richard, 1985 (Box-folder 18: 11)
  - Neier, Aryeh, 1983 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  - Nitze, Paul, 1980 (Box-folder 18: 13)
  - Pickering, Thomas, 1986 (Box-folder 18: 14)
  - Ptacek, Kerry, 1983 (Box-folder 18: 15)
  - Purcell, Jim, undated (Box-folder 18: 16)
  - Quayle, Dan, 1989-1991
    - 1989
      - A-F (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
      - G-M (Box-folder 19: 3-4)
      - N-Z (Box-folder 19: 5, Box-folder 20: 1)
    - 1990
      - A-F (Box-folder 20: 2)
      - G-M (Box-folder 20: 3)
      - N-S (Box-folder 20: 4)
      - T-Z (Box-folder 20: 5, Box-folder 21: 1)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - Undated
      - A-F (Box-folder 21: 3-4)
      - H-W (Box-folder 21: 5-6)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1981-1988
    - Undated-1981 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 22: 5)
  - Rees, John, undated (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - Robinson, Davis, 1982 (Box-folder 22: 7)
  - Rodman, Peter, 1990 (Box-folder 22: 8)
  - Rosenthal, Morton, undated (Box-folder 22: 9)
  - Rostow, Eugene, 1980 (Box-folder 22: 10)
  - Shultz, George, 1981-1991
    - 1981-1983 (Box-folder 22: 11)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - 1986
      - A-M (Box-folder 23: 2)
      - N-Z (Box-folder 23: 3)
    - 1987
      - A-E (Box-folder 23: 4)
      - F (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
      - G-M (Box-folder 24: 3-4)
      - P-S (Box-folder 24: 5-6)
      - T-Y (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - 1988-1991 (Box-folder 25: 2-3)
    - Undated
      - A-C (Box-folder 25: 4-5)
      - D-F (Box-folder 26: 1)
      - G-M (Box-folder 26: 2-3)
      - N-S (Box-folder 26: 4-5)
      - T-W (Box-folder 27: 1)
      - Untitled (Box-folder 27: 2-3)
  - Sherman, William, 1981 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Sigmund, Paul, undated (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - Singer, Max, 1983 (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Smith, N. Shaw, 1983 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Sober, Sidney, 1976 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Solomon, Richard, 1990 (Box-folder 27: 9)
  - Stoessel, William, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  - Stone, Richard, 1984 (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - Theberge, James, 1982 (Box-folder 27: 12)
  - Tull, Theresa, undated (Box-folder 27: 13)
  - Turner, Carlton, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Weigel, George, 1985 (Box-folder 28: 2)
  - Whitehead, John, 1985-1988
    - 1985-1986 (Box-folder 28: 3-4)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 28: 5-6)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 28: 7)
    - Undated (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Whittlesey, Faith, undated (Box-folder 29: 2)
  - Wiesel, Elie, 1981 (Box-folder 29: 3)
  - Wilcox, Philip, 1985 (Box-folder 29: 4)
  - Wolfowitz, Paul, 1983 (Box-folder 29: 5)
  - Wriston, Walter, 1988 (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - Unknown, 1981-1991
    - 1981-1991 (Box-folder 29: 7-8)
    - Undated
      - A-F (Box-folder 29: 9)
      - G-Y (Box-folder 29: 10)
      - Untitled (Box-folder 30: 1)
- Printed Matter, 1938-1991
  - Articles, 1965-1991
    - Undated (Box-folder 30: 2-3)
    - 1965-1979 (Box-folder 30: 4)
    - 1980-1982 (Box-folder 30: 5)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 30: 6, Box-folder 31: 1)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 31: 2)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 31: 3)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 31: 4-5)
    - 1987-1989 (Box-folder 32: 1)
    - 1990-1991 (Box-folder 32: 2-3)
  - Briefings, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 32: 4-5, Box-folder 33: 1)
  - Calendars, 1986 (Box-folder 33: 2-4)
  - Itineraries, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 33: 5, Box-folder 34: 1-2)
  - Minutes, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 34: 3)
  - Pamphlets, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 34: 4-5)
  - Press releases, 1982-1991
    - Undated-1982 (Box-folder 34: 6)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 35: 1-2)
    - 1984-1985 (Box-folder 35: 3)
    - 1986-1991 (Box-folder 35: 4)
  - Programs, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 35: 5, Box-folder 36: 1)
  - Reports, 1938-1991
    - 1938-1979 (Box-folder 36: 2-3)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 36: 4-5)
    - 1981
      - A-C (Box-folder 37: 1-2)
      - E-M (Box-folder 37: 3)
      - N-Z (Box-folder 37: 4)
    - 1982
      - A-M (Box-folder 37: 5, Box-folder 38: 1)
      - N-P (Box-folder 38: 2)
      - Q-Z (Box-folder 38: 3-4)
    - 1983
      - A-B (Box-folder 38: 5-6)
      - C (Box-folder 39: 1)
      - D-F (Box-folder 39: 2)
      - G-M (Box-folder 39: 3-5)
      - N-R (Box-folder 39: 6, Box-folder 40: 1)
      - S-Z (Box-folder 40: 2-3)
    - 1984
      - A-B (Box-folder 40: 4)
      - C (Box-folder 40: 5)
      - D-F (Box-folder 41: 1)
      - G-M (Box-folder 41: 2-3)
      - N (Box-folder 41: 4)
      - P (Box-folder 41: 5)
      - R-S (Box-folder 42: 1-2)
      - T-Z (Box-folder 42: 3-4)
    - 1985
      - A-M (Box-folder 42: 5, Box-folder 43: 1)
      - N-Z (Box-folder 43: 2-3)
    - 1986
      - A-M (Box-folder 43: 4-5)
      - N-Z (Box-folder 43: 6, Box-folder 44: 1)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 44: 2-3)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 44: 4-5)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 44: 6)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 45: 1-2)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 45: 3)
    - Undated
      - A-B (Box-folder 45: 4)
      - C (Box-folder 45: 5)
      - D (Box-folder 46: 1-4)
      - E (Box-folder 46: 5)
      - F (Box-folder 46: 6)
      - G-H (Box-folder 47: 1-2)
      - I (Box-folder 47: 3)
      - J-M (Box-folder 47: 4)
      - N-O (Box-folder 47: 5-6)
      - P (Box-folder 48: 1)
      - R (Box-folder 48: 2)
      - S (Box-folder 48: 3-4)
      - T (Box-folder 49: 1)
      - U-Z (Box-folder 49: 2)
      - Untitled (Box-folder 49: 3-4, Box-folder 50: 1-4)
  - Serial issues, 1979-1990
    - American Education, 1982-1985
      - 1982 - 1983 May (Box-folder 51: 1)
      - 1983 June-December (Box-folder 51: 2)
      - 1984-1985 (Box-folder 51: 3)
    - The American Spectator, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 51: 4)
    - Baltic Bulletin, 1983 (Box-folder 51: 5)
    - Catholicism in Crisis, 1985 (Box-folder 51: 6)
    - The Center Magazine, 1984 (Box-folder 51: 7)
    - Commentary, 1981 (Box-folder 51: 8)
    - Department of State Bulletin, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 52: 1)
    - Fortune, 1990 (Box-folder 52: 2)
    - Freedom Appeals, 1981 (Box-folder 52: 3)
    - Freedom at Issue, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 52: 4)
    - National Review, 1982 (Box-folder 52: 5)
    - New York Times, 1984 (Box-folder 52: 6)
    - Peace Notes, 1979 (Box-folder 52: 7)
    - Pro-Education, 1985 (Box-folder 52: 8)
    - Teen Titans, 1983 (Box-folder 52: 9)
    - Vital Speeches of the Day, 1988 (Box-folder 52: 10)
  - Transcripts, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 52: 11-12)
  - Miscellany, 1985-1991 (Box 53, Box 54)